Maria Snowden Mayor Papers
Maria Snowden Mayor Papers
1814-1934
Mayor, Maria Snowden.
2.5 linear ft.
Correspondence, personal documents, and published material. Correspondence includes that of Audella Hyatt, Alfred G. Mayor, and Harriet Hyatt Mayor.
2604731
Biographical History
Very little is known about Mrs. Mayor. She was the second wife of Alfred Marshall Mayor the noted physicist. Dr. Mayor had a son, Alfred Goldsborough Mayor, by his first wife Katharine Goldsborough. So the second Mrs. Mayor had a stepson.
She and Dr. Mayor also had two children of their own, Joseph Henry and Brantz, but both these boys died young. Mrs. Mayor lived with her husband for a time in Hoboken, N. J. but they moved to Maplewood, N.J. first as a summer home and later permanently. Her stepson Alfred married Harriet Hyatt in 1900 and soon she was a grandmother. She died around 1934 at an elderly age.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Maria Snowden Mayor (Mrs. Alfred Marshall Mayor) Papers contain correspondence, bills and receipts, cards, legal papers, photographs, and published material including articles and newspaper clippings about others, and books.
Correspondence, includes incoming and outgoing correspondence and correspondence to and from others. Subject File, contains an old bank note, bills and receipts, bond notices, cards, snips of children's hair, legal papers, notes of others, and photographs. Published Material, includes articles about others, two books, and newspaper clippings about others.
Arrangement of the Collection
Incoming letters are arranged alphabetically by author and the outgoing letters are arranged chronologically. The letters to and from others are divided into general letters, letters to Mrs. Antoinette Snowden, and Snowden family letters. Subject File and Published Material are arranged alphabetically by type.
Related Material
The has numerous collections for the Hyatt-Mayor families. For information on members of the Hyatt, Mayor, Beebe, and Huntington families see for the finding aids of individual family members.
Subject and Genre Headings
Mayor, Maria Snowden.; Mayer, Alfred M. (Alfred Marshall), 1836-1897.; Hyatt, Audella, 1840-1932.; Mayor, A. Hyatt (Alpheus Hyatt), 1901-1980.; Mayor, Alfred Goldsborough, 1868-1922.; Mayor, Harriet H. (Harriet Hyatt), 1868-1960.; Hyatt family.; Mayor family.; Correspondence.; Receipts (financial records); Legal documents.; Photographs.; Articles.; Books.; Bank notes.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - A - B (Box 1)
    - C - D (Box 1)
    - Cook, Katharine Mayor, See Townsend, Katharine Mayor Cook.
    - F (Box 1)
    - H (Box 1)
    - Hyatt, Audella, 1896; 1900-1902,; 1904-1907; 1908-1913,; 1915-1921,; 1923-1925,; 1931-1932,; undated; 10 folders (Box 1)
    - Hyatt, Harriet, See Mayor, Harriet Hyatt
    - J - L (Box 1)
    - M (Box 1)
    - Mayor, Alfred G., 1884; 1890-1893,; 1896-1897,; 1899-1900,; 1902-1905,; 1907-1911,; 1913-1922,; undated/unknown; 15 folders (Box 2)
    - Mayor, Alfred M. (Box 3)
    - Mayor, Alpheus Hyatt. (Box 3)
    - Mayor, Barbara, See Money, Barbara Mayor.
    - Mayor, Brantz (Box 3)
    - Mayor, various, Charles F., Ellen, Evelyn Griswold, Lewis C. and Virginia Sluder (Box 3)
    - Mayor, Frank B. (Box 3)
    - Mayor, Harriet Hyatt, 1897-1905; 1907-1917; 12 folders (Box 3)
    - Mayor, Harriet Hyatt, 1918-1927; 1929,; 1931-1934,; undated/unidentified; 14 folders (Box 4)
    - Mayor, Joseph Henry (Box 4)
    - Mayor, Katharine, See Townsend, Katharine Mayor Cook.
    - Money, Barbara Mayor (Box 4)
    - N, P, R (Box 4)
    - S (Box 4)
    - Stevens, W. L. (Box 5)
    - Townsend, Katharine Mayor Cook (Box 5)
    - V (Box 5)
    - W (Box 5)
    - Unidentified (Box 5)
  - Outgoing correspondence
    - To Mrs. Charles F. Mayor, 1872-1883; 1889,; 1897,; 1899,; 1933,; undated/unidentified; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence to and from others
    - [Miscellaneous] (Box 5)
    - Letters to Miss Antoinette Snowden (Box 5)
    - Snowden family letters, 1814-1829 (Box 5)
- Subject file
  - Bank Note for 12 ½ cents, Frederictown Branch Bank, 1841 (Frederick, Md.) (Box 5)
  - Bills and receipts (Box 5)
  - Bond notices (Box 5)
  - Cards (Box 5)
  - Children's hair (Box 5)
  - Legal papers (Box 5)
  - Notes of others (Box 5)
  - Photographs (Box 5)
- Published material
  - Article: "Sketch of the Life of Alfred M. Mayor" (Box 5)
  - Books
    - Die Plagen (Box 5)
    - Schlau, Schlauer am Schlausten (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings about others (Box 5)